,text,date,headline,label,ner,ner_labels
0,"KARACHI: The Sindh government has decided to bring down public transport fares by 7 per cent due to massive reduction in petroleum product prices by the federal government, Geo News reported.Sources said reduction in fares will be applicable on public transport, rickshaw, taxi and other means of traveling.Meanwhile, Karachi Transport Ittehad (KTI) has refused to abide by the government decision.KTI President Irshad Bukhari said the commuters are charged the lowest fares in Karachi as compare to other parts of the country, adding that 80pc vehicles run on Compressed Natural Gas (CNG). Bukhari said Karachi transporters will cut fares when decrease in CNG prices will be made.                        










",1/1/2015,sindh govt decides to cut public transport fares by 7pc kti rej,business,"['KARACHI', 'Sindh', 'Geo', 'News', 'Karachi', 'Transport', 'Ittehad', 'KTI', 'KTI', 'Irshad', 'Bukhari', 'Karachi', 'Compressed', 'Natural', 'Gas', 'CNG', 'Bukhari', 'Karachi', 'CNG']","['I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC']"
1,"HONG KONG:  Hong Kong shares opened 0.66 percent lower Monday following a tepid lead from Wall Street, as the first full week of the new year kicked off.The benchmark Hang Seng Index dipped 158.63 points to 23,699.19. 










",1/5/2015,hong kong stocks open 0.66 percent lower,business,"['Hong', 'Kong', 'Wall', 'Street', 'Hang', 'Seng']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC']"
2,"New York: Oil prices tumbled Tuesday to fresh 5.5-year lows as Saudi Arabia blamed weak global economic growth and said it will stick to its guns on production policy.US benchmark West Texas Intermediate for delivery in February sank $2.11 to $47.93 a barrel, a low last witnessed in late April 2009.Brent North Sea crude for delivery in February dived $2.01 to $51.10 per barrel, the lowest level since early May 2009.""The market is still worried that there are no signs that the supply glut will start falling,"" Nordea Markets analyst Thina Margrethe Saltvedt told AFP.James Williams of WTRG said the weakness in the market could take prices below $40 a barrel.""Basically, there are continuing concerns about OPEC not cutting back, particularly Saudi Arabia, and US production continuing to grow,"" he said.Saudi Arabia´s Crown Prince Salman, in a speech on behalf of ailing King Abdullah Tuesday, said weak growth was to blame for the price fall, which has sliced deeply into the income of the world´s largest exporter.""This development is not new in the oil market, and the kingdom has in the past dealt with it firmly and wisely,"" he said, adding that Saudi Arabia will maintain its ""same approach"" towards the market.That appeared to confirm Riyadh´s determination to defend its market share rather than reduce output, even if that pushes prices lower.On Monday Saudi Arabia reportedly cut its European and US export prices in order to maintain market share. (AFP)                        










",1/7/2015,oil hits new 5.5 year lows as saudis defend ,business,"['New', 'York', 'Saudi', 'Arabia', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'Brent', 'North', 'Sea', 'Nordea', 'Markets', 'Thina', 'Margrethe', 'Saltvedt', 'AFP', 'James', 'Williams', 'WTRG', 'OPEC', 'Saudi', 'Arabia', 'US', 'Saudi', 'Arabia´s', 'Salman', 'Abdullah', 'Saudi', 'Arabia', 'Riyadh´s', 'Saudi', 'Arabia', 'European', 'US', 'AFP']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG']"
3,"KARACHI: Strong bulls on Friday pulled the benchmark KSE-100 Index at Karachi Stock Exchange (KSE) and taking it across the psychological barrier of 33,000 points with a single day’s gain of 207 points.The investors remained active right from the opening bells of today’s trade, contributing 207 points to the major index and a close at 33,324 points – a new record in Pakistan’s stock market history.According to stock market experts, the investors are interested in taking fresh positions in the expectations of discount rate going further down as a result of a visible decline in inflation rate.They said the stock market of Pakistan has earned the honour of being considered as one of the most successful markets of this region in 2014 during which investors booked over 25 percent profits.  










",1/9/2015,bullish kse jumps over 33000 psychological barrier,business,"['KARACHI', 'KSE', '-', '100', 'Index', 'Karachi', 'Stock', 'Exchange', 'KSE', 'Pakistans', 'Pakistan']","['I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
4,"Singapore: Oil fell further in Asia Monday, with weak demand and a supply glut putting relentless pressure on prices already at their lowest in five and a half years, analysts said.US benchmark West Texas Intermediate (WTI) for February delivery was down 81 cents at $47.55 a barrel in mid-morning trade and Brent crude for February dropped 90 cents to 49.21.""The fundamental factors have not changed much. There is an oversupply and demand is weak,"" said Daniel Ang, an investment analyst with Phillip Futures in Singapore.The outlook is for prices to decline further this week, with WTI seen touching a low of $45 and Brent $48, Ang told AFP.""Oil prices continued to tumble and headed for a seventh straight weekly loss as key producers show no sign of cutting output in the face of a supply glut,"" Singapore´s United Overseas Bank said in a commentary.Crude prices have lost more than half their value since the middle of last year when they sat well above $100 a barrel.Members of the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries, which pumps about 40 percent of the world´s oil, have said they will not cut production despite excessive supplies. (AFP)                        










",1/12/2015,oil falls further in asian trad,business,"['Singapore', 'Asia', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'WTI', 'Brent', 'Daniel', 'Ang', 'Phillip', 'Futures', 'Singapore', 'WTI', 'Brent', 'Ang', 'AFP', 'Singapore´s', 'United', 'Overseas', 'Bank', 'Organization', 'of', 'the', 'Petroleum', 'Countries', 'AFP']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
5,"KARACHI: Wholesale market rates for sugar dropped to less than Rs 50 per kg following the resumption of sugar cane crushing by sugar mills in Sindh.Within two days, the rate dropped by Rs 1.70 to Rs 49.80 per kg in Karachi Whole Sale Market.According to dealers, the resumption of sugar cane crushing by the mills stabilised the supply to the market with an immediate effect on price as well.Industry experts said that the quality of sugar cane is excellent in Sindh and approximately 100 kg of sugar cane can produce 11 kg of sugar.  










",1/13/2015,sugar prices drop to rs 49.80 in sind,business,"['KARACHI', 'Sindh', 'Karachi', 'Sindh']","['I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
6,"TOKYO: Tokyo stocks opened 0.74 percent lower on Wednesday, hit by the yen´s rise and drops on Wall Street on worries about falling oil prices.The Nikkei 225 index at the Tokyo Stock Exchange lost 125.89 to 16,961.82 at the start.In New York on Tuesday the Dow Jones Industrial Average dropped 0.15 percent and the broad-based S&P 500 fell 0.26 percent, overshadowed by worries about sliding crude oil prices.The yen rose against other currencies on safe-haven buying, a negative for Japanese exporters as the stronger currency makes them less competitive abroad and erodes profits when repatriated.The dollar was at 117.72 yen early Wednesday, down from 117.90 yen in New York Tuesday afternoon and rates above 118 yen seen in Tokyo earlier Tuesday.The euro also fell after a key European central banker expressed support for monetary stimulus.The common European currency bought 138.69 yen and $1.1776 against 138.84 yen and $1.1777 in US trade.The ruble´s drop took a breather early Wednesday after plunging by around 5 percent on Tuesday as global oil prices tumbled towards a six-year low.The dollar was at 65.28 against the ruble on Wednesday against levels above 66 seen on Tuesday. 










",1/14/2015,tokyo stocks open 0.74 percent lower,business,"['TOKYO', 'Tokyo', 'Wall', 'Street', 'Nikkei', '225', 'Tokyo', 'Stock', 'Exchange', 'New', 'York', 'Dow', 'Jones', 'Industrial', 'Average', 'S', '&', 'P', 'Japanese', 'New', 'York', 'Tokyo', 'European', 'European', 'US']","['I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC']"
7,"HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks edged up 0.24 percent in early trade Thursday despite a fourth successive day of losses on Wall Street.The benchmark Hang Seng Index added 56.75 points to 24,169.35. 










",1/15/2015,hong kong stocks open 0.24 percent higher,business,"['Hong', 'Kong', 'Wall', 'Street', 'Hang', 'Seng']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC']"
8,"ISLAMABAD: Long queues of vehicles on fuel stations were visible in different parts of the country as the petrol became rare commodity on Thursday.Federal Minister for Petroleum Shahid Khaqan Abbasi says ""it may take up to ten days to bring the situation to normality"".He claimed that northern areas of Pakistan had been facing the petrol shortage. The minister cited the recent decline in petroleum prices and delay in a shipment as reasons for the shortage.He said situation would improve as soon as shipment reached Pakistan. Sources told Geo News hat due to financial restraints the Pakistan State Oil has been unable import petrol. 










",1/16/2015,govt may take up to ten days to overcome petrol shortag,business,"['Federal', 'Petroleum', 'Shahid', 'Khaqan', 'Abbasi', 'Pakistan', 'Pakistan', 'Geo', 'News', 'Pakistan', 'State', 'Oil']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
9,"ISLAMABAD: A two member committee tasked to probe the prevailing petrol shortage on Tuesday said that the situation was a serious failure on the part of OGRA (Oil and Gas Regulatory Authority) as a regulator. The committee presented its initial findings to Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif in a meeting held here under his chairmanship to review the petroleum situation in the country.The PM directed to make structural changes to ensure that such a situation never arises again. The meeting endorsed the earlier decision of suspending four senior officials responsible for the crisis.The meeting also decided that Deputy Managing Director Pakistan State Oil (PSO) Sohail Butt was also equally responsible and ordered for his suspension as well.Meanwhile, Petroleum Minister Shahid Khaqan Abbasi said that he was never satisfied with the performance of OGRA and the authority’s performance as a regulator was not just dismal for petrol but was also same for gas.Petrol crisis: Day 8 The petrol crisis has entered its eight day in Punjab as commuters continue their search for fuel. Long queues are seen at stations which are open with people complaining of waiting for several hours for just a litre of petrol. The All Pakistan Petroleum Dealers Association said that 5.7 mn liters of petrol has been disbursed to fuel stations across Punjab during the last three days and another 1.8 mn liters will be dispersed by tonight.However, according to the Petroleum Dealers Association, the state of affairs is improving and the chaos at stations was only due to mismanagement of the pumps and had nothing to do with the supply.The association further said that all fuel stations have been directed to meet the demands of the commuters with the provided supply of petrol, as well as all stations should stop providing petrol to customers with bottles and canisters in order to avoid queues. 










",1/20/2015,report presented to pm holds ogra responsible for fuel crisi,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'OGRA', 'Oil', 'and', 'Gas', 'Regulatory', 'Authority', 'Nawaz', 'Sharif', 'Pakistan', 'State', 'Oil', 'PSO', 'Sohail', 'Butt', 'Petroleum', 'Shahid', 'Khaqan', 'Abbasi', 'OGRA', 'Punjab', 'All', 'Pakistan', 'Petroleum', 'Dealers', 'Association', 'Punjab', 'Petroleum', 'Dealers', 'Association']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
10,"ISLAMABAD: The National Electric Power Regulatory Authority (NEPRA) on Wednesday said that a notification has been issued after November’s fuel adjustment regarding a relief on electricity charges for Karachi’s consumers.According to the notification, consumers will benefit by a reduction of Rs. 1.73 per unit which would reflect in bills for March 2015.NEPRA had proposed the reduction during the first week of January and after approval it issued the notification today.   










",1/21/2015,notification issued for reduction in electricity charges for karachi nepr,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'National', 'Electric', 'Power', 'Regulatory', 'Authority', 'NEPRA', 'Karachis', 'NEPRA']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG']"
11,"ISLAMABAD: The Economic Coordination Committee of the Cabinet (ECC) on Friday approved export of 1.2 million tons of wheat and imposed a bans on import of wheat byproducts. Federal Minister for Finance Senator Ishaq Dar chaired the meeting and approved the export of 1.2 million tons of wheat out of the surplus stocks available in Punjab and Sindh.Accordingly, Punjab will export 800,000 tons while Sindh has been allocated export quota of 400,000 tons of wheat. Punjab will get a subsidy of Rs55 per metric ton for export while for Sindh this subsidy would be Rs45 per metric ton.Taking notice of unhindered import of wheat byproducts, the ECC also issued instructions for immediate ban on their import.The ECC considered a proposal moved by the Ministry of States and Frontier Regions (Safron) and approved the provision of 30,000 tons of wheat to the United Nations World Food Programme for distribution among Temporarily Displaced Persons (TDPs), catering for the period up to March 2015.The ECC also observed that in case of further requirements, Safron could revert to the forum with a fresh proposal.The ECC considered and approved a proposal by the Water and Power Minstry to attract private sector investment in transmission line projects with the inclusion of upfront tariff as an option. The ECC also accorded approval for the extension of GSA between OGDCL and Fauji Kabirwala Power Company Limited (FKPCL) for provision of 20 mmcfd of gas at the earliest but not later than February 1. Till that time, LNG is made available to the company for power generation. At its maximum generation capacity utilisation, the plant will generate 157 MW of electricity.The ECC approved Issuance of Policy directive to NEPRA to build in costs incurred by the power sector into the tariff without affecting the end consumer.The committee also approved the re-lending of the buyer credit loan to PAEC as per actual terms and conditions available to the Government of Pakistan. Based on the above approval, the revised rate comes to nine per cent comprising actual cost of loan and exchange rate risk.                        










",1/23/2015,ecc approves export of 1.2 million tons of ,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Economic', 'Coordination', 'Committee', 'Cabinet', 'ECC', 'Federal', 'Finance', 'Ishaq', 'Dar', 'Punjab', 'Sindh', 'Punjab', 'Sindh', 'Punjab', 'Sindh', 'ECC', 'ECC', 'Ministry', 'of', 'States', 'and', 'Frontier', 'Regions', 'Safron', 'United', 'Nations', 'World', 'Food', 'Programme', 'Temporarily', 'Displaced', 'Persons', 'TDPs', 'ECC', 'Safron', 'ECC', 'Water', 'and', 'Power', 'Minstry', 'ECC', 'GSA', 'OGDCL', 'Fauji', 'Kabirwala', 'Power', 'Company', 'Limited', 'FKPCL', 'LNG', 'ECC', 'NEPRA', 'PAEC', 'Pakistan']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
12,"ISLAMABAD: The National Electric Power Regulatory Authority (NEPRA) on Friday said that it was unlawful of K-Electric to collect meter rent of Rs. 7.50 per customer.According to a NEPRA spokesman, the regulatory authority has immediately stopped K-Electric from collecting the rent. It has also directed the organisation to return all the collected rent so far back to about 2.2 million customers. 










",1/23/2015,nepra prevents k electric from collecting meter r,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'National', 'Electric', 'Power', 'Regulatory', 'Authority', 'NEPRA', 'K', '-', 'Electric', 'NEPRA', 'K', '-', 'Electric']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
13,"ISLAMABAD: Finance Minister Ishaq Dar here on Sunday chaired a briefing session by managing director Pak-Brunei Investment Company seeking details of its present investment financing profile and immediate future plans. Pak-Brunei Investment Company is an investment finance company established as a joint venture between government of Pakistan and Brunei Investment Agency (BIA) that commenced operations in August 2007 said a press release. Managing Director Ayesha Aziz said that Pak-Brunei plans to increase its small and medium enterprise footprint across various regions of the country. She said that the company was in final stages of launching a modarba fund as its special future venture. The First Fund based on PE model will be established by March 2015.Pak-Brunei also has plans for establishment of specialized vehicles for warehousing collateral management. Finance Minister appreciated the company’s 100% recovery ratios particularly in SME financing and handling projects facing financial distress.  










",1/25/2015,finance minister apprised on pak brunei investment ,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Ishaq', 'Dar', 'Pak', '-', 'Brunei', 'Investment', 'Company', 'Pak', '-', 'Brunei', 'Investment', 'Company', 'Pakistan', 'Brunei', 'Investment', 'Agency', 'BIA', 'Ayesha', 'Aziz', 'Pak', '-', 'Brunei', 'Pak', '-', 'Brunei', 'SME']","['I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC']"
14,"ISLAMABAD: In a move to give relief to consumers, sources in the Finance Ministry said on Tuesday that the price of petrol and petroleum products are expected to decrease further from February 1.According to sources, the price of petrol is expected to be slashed by Rs 10 per litre, High Speed Diesel by Rs 8.50 per litre, Light Diesel by Rs 11 per litre, HOBC by Rs 14 per litre, and Kerosene by Rs 12 per litre.Global crude oil prices have fallen by 50 percent since June 2014, and to provide consistent relief to consumers, the Pakistan government has decreased the price of petrol by Rs 29 since the last four months and brought the price of Diesel down by Rs 23 in the same time frame.Fuel crisis in the country began last week when Pakistan State Oil (PSO) was forced to slash imports because banks refused to extend any more credit to the government-owned company, which supplies 80 percent of the country´s oil.The shortfall led to long queues of angry motorists at petrol stations, though these have since dissipated as fuel supplies have reached the pumps. 










",1/27/2015,petrol price expected to be slashed by rs 10 per litr,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Finance', 'Ministry', 'High', 'Speed', 'Diesel', 'Light', 'Diesel', 'HOBC', 'Kerosene', 'Pakistan', 'Diesel', 'Pakistan', 'State', 'Oil', 'PSO']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
15,"New York: Oil prices rebounded Tuesday from six-year lows as the dollar weakened after disappointing US economic data.The US benchmark, West Texas Intermediate (WTI) for March delivery, rose $1.08 (2.4 percent) to close at $45.16 a barrel.Brent North Sea crude for March settled at $49.60 a barrel in London, up $1.44 from Monday´s closing level.""The market has found a bottom in the mid-40 range,"" said Kyle Cooper of IAF Advisors.Crude futures sank Monday to their lowest closing levels since early 2009. Crude has shed nearly 60 percent of its value in an almost uninterrupted slide since June due to a supply glut, largely boosted by robust US shale-oil production and weaker global economic growth.The greenback has been strengthening for months, making dollar-priced oil relatively more expensive, adding to the pressure on the oil market.A slight easing in the dollar Tuesday against major rival currencies such as the euro, yen and pound underpinned the buying, Cooper said.""I didn´t see anything bullish today"" for WTI, he said. ""Equities are down, durable goods (are) not that good.""New orders for long-lasting US industrial goods unexpectedly fell in December, by a steep 3.4 percent, signaling some persistent weakness in the manufacturing sector.Saudi Aramco, the world´s largest oil company in terms of crude production and exports, acknowledged that prices have fallen too far but it was up to the market, not OPEC producers, to shore them up.""It´s too low for everybody,"" said Khalid al-Falih, the president of the state-owned energy giant, told a conference in Riyadh. ""I think even consumers start to suffer in the long term.""Falih also said US shale-oil production is important for the world´s long-term energy future and Saudi Aramco has earmarked an additional $7 billion for its own shale projects.The kingdom is the leading exporter and top producer in the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries, which provides about a third of global oil supplies.In November, OPEC resisted calls to reduce output in the face of falling prices, keeping its output ceiling at 30 million barrels per day in a decision that exacerbated the global price slump. (AFP)                        










",1/28/2015,oil rebounds sharply from six year lows as dollar ,business,"['New', 'York', 'US', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'WTI', 'Brent', 'North', 'Sea', 'London', 'Kyle', 'Cooper', 'IAF', 'Advisors', 'Crude', 'US', 'Cooper', 'WTI', 'US', 'Saudi', 'Aramco', 'OPEC', 'Khalid', 'al', '-', 'Falih', 'Riyadh', 'Falih', 'US', 'Saudi', 'Aramco', 'Organization', 'Petroleum', 'Countries', 'OPEC']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG']"
16,"New York: Oil tumbled to near a six-year low Wednesday as US crude stocks soared to a record high, sparking fresh fears over the growing global supply glut.US benchmark West Texas Intermediate (WTI) for March delivery dropped $1.78 to $44.45 a barrel on the New York Mercantile Exchange, its lowest close since March 2009.European benchmark Brent North Sea crude for March delivery lost $1.13 at $48.47 a barrel in London.Data showed that US crude supplies surged 8.9 million barrels to 406.7 million in the week ending January 23, according to the US Department of Energy.That was the highest level since the US government began keeping weekly records in 1982. It is also above monthly data since April 1931.""It´s not a pretty picture,"" said Bart Melek, head of commodity strategy at TD Securities. ""We´re seeking bottom but I don´t think we´re there yet.""The oil market has collapsed by more than 50 percent since June, plagued by plentiful crude supplies, weak global demand and the decision of the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries to let prices fall.""If proof were needed that oil prices remain constrained by too much supply, this afternoon´s US inventory data confirmed it,"" said CMC Markets analyst Michael Hewson.""As such, prices could well have further to fall with prospects of a drop below $40 a barrel becoming a reality in the short to medium term."" (AFP)                        










",1/29/2015,oil slumps as us crude reserves surge to record hig,business,"['New', 'York', 'US', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'WTI', 'New', 'York', 'Mercantile', 'Exchange', 'European', 'Brent', 'North', 'Sea', 'London', 'US', 'US', 'Department', 'of', 'Energy', 'US', 'Bart', 'Melek', 'TD', 'Securities', 'Organization', 'of', 'Petroleum', 'Exporting', 'Countries', 'US', 'CMC', 'Markets', 'Michael', 'Hewson', 'AFP']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG']"
17,"ISLAMABAD:  Federal Minister for Finance Ishaq Dar on Saturday announced a five percent increase in the General Sales Tax (GST) on petroleum products.Dar said that the increment would enable a recovery of 12 billion rupees.The minister, however, went on to say that the ministry would still face a loss of 40 billion rupees.Earlier today, Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif announced a decrease in the price of petroleum products.Petrol has been decreased by Rs 7.99, Hi-Octane by Rs 11.82, Light Diesel by Rs 9.56 and kerosene oil by Rs 10.48 per litre. 










",1/31/2015,finance minister announces five percent increase in gst on pol produ,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Federal', 'Ishaq', 'Dar', 'Dar', 'Nawaz', 'Sharif', 'Light', 'Diesel']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC']"
18,"NEW YORK: US authorities are investigating the credit rating agency Moody's over its glowing assessments of mortgage deals in the runup to the 2008 financial crisis, The Wall Street Journal reported Sunday.Citing people familiar with the situation, the newspaper said Justice Department officials had met with several former Moody's executives. It wasn't yet clear if the probe would result in a lawsuit.If the investigation is confirmed, Moody's would become the second major US credit-rating firm in the Justice Department's crosshairs, after a case against Standard & Poor's.S&P is expected to within days agree to pay $1.37 billion to settle lawsuits over its rosy grading of mortgage bonds in the financial crisis, sources told AFP.Neither Moody's nor the Justice Department were immediately reachable for comment Sunday.US authorities are probing whether the firm compromised its standards to score deals, the Journal reported, and the focus is on residential mortgage deals from about 2004 to 2007.Positive ratings on what turned out to be extremely risky mortgage deals, known as subprime loans, were a main cause of the 2008 financial collapse.Investors rely on rating firms' grades to assess risk.Numerous banks have already paid huge fines and settlements for their roles in packaging and selling the bonds as low-risk, solid investments. 










",2/2/2015,us probes moodys rating agency,business,"['NEW', 'US', 'Moody', ""'"", 's', 'The', 'Wall', 'Street', 'Journal', 'Justice', 'Department', 'Moody', ""'"", 's', 'Moody', ""'"", 's', 'US', 'Justice', 'Department', 'Standard', '&', 'Poor', ""'"", 's', 'S', '&', 'P', 'AFP', 'Moody', ""'"", 's', 'Justice', 'Department', 'US', 'Journal']","['I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG']"
19,"London: Global oil prices slid Wednesday following a three-day rally as dealers were divided on whether the commodity has bottomed out after a plunge of nearly 60 percent since June. US benchmark West Texas Intermediate (WTI) for delivery in March shed $1.72 to stand at $51.33 a barrel compared with Tuesday´s close.Brent North Sea crude for March slid $1.15 a barrel to trade at $56.76 in London afternoon trade.WTI had soared $3.48 Tuesday to record its highest finish since December 31, while Brent jumped $3.16 to a similar closing peak, as dealers cheered signs that the oil industry is tightening exploration activities to cap a supply glut.Ken Hasegawa, an energy trading manager at Newedge Group in Tokyo, said the crude market was ""extremely volatile"" after the three-day rally that began Friday saw prices surge nearly 20 percent.""It has become increasingly difficult to discern the direction of the prices of crude oil, but the fundamentals remain unchanged,"" Hasegawa told AFP. He added that prices could ""fluctuate by increasing up to $10 and falling up to $10"" in the short term.Deep cuts in capital spending by major oil companies, including new announcements Tuesday by BP and BG Group, had suggested there would be tighter supplies in the future. The Baker Hughes North America rig count report for the week to January 30 showed a drop of 128 rigs to 1,937. That compared with 2,393 a year ago.Some analysts however remain doubtful that the current oil price rebound will be sustained as supplies still outweigh demand in the immediate term.The oil market has lost more than half its value since June largely owing to a surge in global reserves boosted by robust US shale oil production. The problem was exacerbated in November after OPEC decided to maintain output levels despite plunging prices.The 12-nation Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) cartel pumps about 30 percent of global crude supplies. (AFP)                        










",2/4/2015,oil prices slide after rally,business,"['London', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'WTI', 'Brent', 'North', 'Sea', 'London', 'WTI', 'Brent', 'Ken', 'Hasegawa', 'Newedge', 'Group', 'Tokyo', 'Hasegawa', 'AFP', 'BP', 'BG', 'Group', 'Baker', 'Hughes', 'North', 'America', 'US', 'OPEC', 'Organization', 'Petroleum', 'Exporting', 'OPEC', 'AFP']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
20,"ISLAMABAD: Federal State Minister for Water and Power Abid Sher Ali on Wednesday said that K-Electric should step up production of electricity with immediate effect and end load shedding.The minister while claiming that there is no unannounced load shedding in the country, he added that the few areas facing load shedding was due to line losses.He went on to say that Sindh faced more load shedding because of 131 feeders facing line losses and that urban areas were facing six to seven hours while rural areas were facing eight to nine hours of load shedding. He added that the industries were facing four hours of load shedding.However, PPP’s Fahmida Mirza contradicted the minister’s figures saying that he is wrong about his statistics and that Badin was facing 20 to 22 hours of load shedding.   










",2/4/2015,no unannounced load shedding anywhere in the country abid sher ali,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Federal', 'State', 'Water', 'and', 'Power', 'Abid', 'Sher', 'Ali', 'K', '-', 'Electric', 'Sindh', 'PPPs', 'Fahmida', 'Mirza', 'Badin']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC']"
21,"London: Oil prices fell further Thursday as the market was awash with ample US supplies and the dollar strengthened, dealers said.US benchmark West Texas Intermediate (WTI) for delivery in March shed $1.32 to trade at $49.09 a barrel compared with Wednesday´s close.Brent North Sea crude for March slid $1.12 to stand at 55.28 a barrel around midday in London. Crude prices on Wednesday snapped a three-day rally, with WTI sinking 8.7 percent owing to climbing US crude stockpiles.Analysts said prices are weighed down also by the euro´s fall on news that the European Central Bank had cut off Greek banks´ access to a key source of much-needed cash.In a decision that rattled global financial markets, the ECB said Wednesday it would no longer allow Greek banks to use government debt, which has a junk rating, as collateral for loans.""The Greek situation is worth keeping an eye on as it massively impacts the value of the euro against the US dollar,"" said Shailaja Nair, associate editorial director at energy information provider Platts.A sinking euro makes dollar-priced oil more expensive, denting demand and adding downward pressure on crude prices, which have already been battered by a supply glut and weak demand.Crude has lost more than half its value since June, when prices were at more than $100 a barrel.Global supplies have been boosted by surging US shale oil production and a decision by the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries in November to keep current output levels. (AFP)                        










",2/5/2015,oil prices extend ,business,"['London', 'US', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'WTI', 'Brent', 'North', 'Sea', 'London', 'WTI', 'US', 'European', 'Central', 'Bank', 'Greek', 'ECB', 'Greek', 'Greek', 'US', 'Shailaja', 'Nair', 'Platts', 'US', 'Organization', 'of', 'the', 'Petroleum', 'Exporting', 'Countries', 'AFP']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
22,"DUBAI: Talks between Pakistan and the International Monetary Fund (IMF) concluded successfully on Thursday, with the IMF agreeing to release $518 million by end of March as the next tranche of the three-year $6.6bn Extended Fund Facility (EFF) programme.“The mission and the Pakistani authorities have reached staff-level understandings on a Memorandum of Economic and Financial Policies on the sixth review of the program, which, upon approval by the IMF’s Management, will be discussed by the IMF Executive Board. ""Upon completion of the review, SDR 360 million (about US$518 million) would be made available to Pakistan,” said the outgoing chief of the IMF Mission to Pakistan Jeffery Franks.Newly-announced Chief of IMF Mission to Pakistan, Herald Finger, will replace Franks after the talks.At a jointly held press conference with the IMF staff in Dubai, Finance Minister Ishaq Dar reiterated that there would be no increase in gas and electricity prices. Pakistan also informed the IMF of its expenditure of Rs. 150 billion on the implementation of the National Action Plan (NAP) as well as repatriation of Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs).Also agreed upon was Rs.60 billion in tax cuts for Pakistan, while it was decided that the target for tax cuts should reach Rs. 2750 million by June.Dar said that Pakistan’s foreign exchange reserves have increased to over $15 billion, entitling the country to receive subsidised loans.However, due to the price reduction of petrol in the country, tax revenue decreased to Rs. 68 billion. “Tax revenues were below the second-quarter indicative target by about 0.1 percent of GDP due in part to legal challenges to some revenue measures and to the fiscal effects of the plunge in international oil prices,” said a press statement from the IMF mission. “While progress has been made in addressing the structural impediments to higher and more inclusive growth, important challenges remain, such as steps to enhance the independence of the SBP, permanently resolve energy sector deficiencies, complete the legal framework for deposit insurance, and privatize or restructure public enterprises,” noted the IMF.                        










",2/5/2015,pak imf talks conclude agreement for release of 518 milli,business,"['Pakistan', 'International', 'Monetary', 'Fund', 'IMF', 'IMF', 'Extended', 'Fund', 'Facility', 'EFF', 'Pakistani', 'IMFs', 'Management', 'IMF', 'Executive', 'Board', 'US', '$', 'Pakistan', 'IMF', 'Mission', 'Pakistan', 'Jeffery', 'Franks', 'IMF', 'Mission', 'Pakistan', 'Herald', 'Finger', 'Franks', 'IMF', 'Dubai', 'Ishaq', 'Dar', 'Pakistan', 'IMF', 'National', 'Action', 'Plan', 'NAP', 'IDPs', 'Pakistan', 'Dar', 'Pakistans', 'IMF', 'IMF']","['I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
23,"KARACHI: The final shipment of Chinese manufactured Rail Engines arrived in Pakistan on Friday. Federal Railways Minister, Khwaja Saad Rafique says, the inclusion of the new engines will help ease the shortfall faced by Pakistan Railways. The shipment includes 2000 and 3000-horse-power engines which will be used to pull freight bogeys. Rafique told journalists, the inclusion of 15 new engines has brought Pakistan Railways total strength to 268 engines however more engines are still required.  










",2/6/2015,final shipment of 15 chinese engines arrives at karachi por,business,"['KARACHI', 'Chinese', 'Rail', 'Engines', 'Pakistan', 'Federal', 'Railways', 'Khwaja', 'Saad', 'Rafique', 'Pakistan', 'Railways', 'Rafique', 'Pakistan', 'Railways']","['I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
24,"London: Oil prices extended gains on Friday at the end of a volatile trading week, as markets awaited the release of key US jobs data.US benchmark West Texas Intermediate (WTI) for March delivery jumped $1.41 from Thursday´s close to $51.89 a barrel.Brent North Sea crude for March rallied $1.64 to $58.21 a barrel in London afternoon deals. WTI on Thursday jumped $2.73 in New York and Brent advanced $2.41, erasing earlier losses. ""It has been a fairly volatile but robust week for the oil market,"" said Myrto Sokou, senior research analyst at Sucden brokers.""Crude oil inventories continue to remain fairly high following ongoing large builds of crude stocks in recent weeks.""All eyes were on the United States and its eagerly-awaited jobs report due Friday that is expected to show the world´s biggest economy added 235,000 jobs last month, a slowdown from December, according to analysts´ forecasts.Oil prices plunged by about 60 percent from their June peaks to a six-year low last week, largely owing to a surge in global reserves boosted by robust US shale production.The problem was exacerbated in November after the OPEC cartel insisted that it would maintain output levels despite plunging prices. The 12-nation group pumps about 30 percent of global crude. (AFP)                        










",2/6/2015,oil extends gains before us jobs d,business,"['London', 'US', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'WTI', 'Brent', 'North', 'Sea', 'London', 'WTI', 'New', 'York', 'Brent', 'Myrto', 'Sokou', 'Sucden', 'United', 'States', 'US', 'OPEC', 'AFP']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
25,"ISLAMABAD: The Ministry of Water and Power issued a statement on Friday saying that the contract to supply 650MW of electricity to K-Electric cannot be renewed.The ministry went on to say that K-Electric should ensure its own production at full capacity to meet the demands.It further said that in case of an emergency shortage, at most 200 to 300MW could be provided.A summary of the decision has been sent to Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif.According to a K-Electric spokesperson, he warned that if the supply is stopped then there could be a possible blackout in the city as the company has no backup plan. He also said that the matter of the ministry not supplying the requirement is sub judice and could lead to contempt of court. Meanwhile, Karachi Chamber of Commerce & Industry President Iftikhar Ahmed Vohra said that if the national grid fails to provide the required demand, industrial production may be heavily affected.He demanded from the government that it should reconsider the supply of 650MW and include it in the contract.On January 26, the ministry had directed the National Power Control Centre (NPCC) not to suspend electricity supply to K-Electric following the expiry of the power distributor’s 5-year agreement for 650 MW supply on January 25. According to sources, a renewed contract with fresh conditions was under consideration earlier. 










",2/6/2015,contract for 650mw supply to k electric cannot be renewed ministry,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Ministry', 'of', 'Water', 'and', 'Power', 'K', '-', 'Electric', 'K', '-', 'Electric', 'Nawaz', 'Sharif', 'K', '-', 'Electric', 'Karachi', 'Chamber', 'of', 'Commerce', '&', 'Industry', 'Iftikhar', 'Ahmed', 'Vohra', 'National', 'Power', 'Control', 'Centre', 'NPCC', 'K', '-', 'Electric']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
26,"TOKYO: Tokyo stocks opened 1.09 percent higher on Friday, with investor sentiment supported by sharp gains on Wall Street and assurances that Greek banks will get liquidity funding.The Nikkei 225 index at the Tokyo Stock Exchange gained 191.56 points to 17,696.18 at the start.The Dow Jones Industrial Average jumped 1.20 percent Thursday on surging oil prices and merger activity by Pfizer.The euro rebounded as emergency funding was promised for Greek banks.The common European currency bought $1.1472 and 134.83 yen early Friday, compared with $1.1475 and 134.89 yen in New York Thursday afternoon.The euro plunged on Wednesday after the European Central Bank said it would not longer allow Greek banks to use government debt as collateral for loans.But on Thursday assurances that the banks could still tap the ECB´s emergency liquidity assistance programme helped quell fears of an immediate banking crisis.The access should help protect them against a possible run by depositors while Athens seeks to renegotiate its international bailout with creditors.The dollar was at 117.51 yen against 117.55 yen in US trade Thursday as investors waited for a key US jobs report to be released later Friday. 










",2/6/2015,tokyo stocks open up 1.09 per,business,"['TOKYO', 'Tokyo', 'Wall', 'Street', 'Greek', 'Nikkei', 'Tokyo', 'Stock', 'Exchange', 'Dow', 'Jones', 'Industrial', 'Average', 'Pfizer', 'Greek', 'European', 'New', 'York', 'European', 'Central', 'Bank', 'Greek', 'ECB´s', 'Athens', 'US', 'US']","['I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
27,"ISLAMABAD: The consistent fall in the price of petrol saw a record sale in the month of January, with a 32 percent increase as compared to January 2014.Consumers across the country bought 0.39 million tonnes of petrol in January this year.According to industry sources, the price difference between petrol and compressed natural gas (CNG) dropped from 56 percent in January 2014 to 31 percent in January 2015.Global crude oil prices have fallen by 50 percent since June 2014, and to provide consistent relief to consumers, the Pakistan government has decreased the price of petrol by Rs 29 since the last four months and brought the price of Diesel down by Rs 23 in the same time frame. 










",2/7/2015,january 2015 saw record sale of petrol in paki,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'CNG', 'Pakistan']","['I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC']"
28,"London: Oil prices advanced further Monday with buying boosted by a dip in North American crude production, while a robust US jobs report also provided support, analysts said. US benchmark West Texas Intermediate for delivery in March advanced $1 to $52.69 a barrel compared with Friday´s close.Brent North Sea crude for March won 63 cents to stand at $58.43 a barrel in London afternoon trade.Last week saw WTI surge seven percent and Brent add 9.4 percent, their best weekly gains since February 2011.Nicholas Teo, market analyst at CMC Markets in Singapore, said the gains were ""motivated by supply-side influences"" in the United States.A survey by US oil services firm Baker Hughes Inc released Friday showed the number of rigs drilling for oil in the United States fell by 83 to 1,140 in the week to February 6. The dip followed a cut of 94 rigs the previous week.Bloomberg News reported that the rig count was standing at its lowest level since December 2011.The drop, coupled with announcements of deep cuts in capital spending by major oil companies including BP and BG Group, suggests tighter supplies in the future.Oil prices have plunged by about 50 percent from their June peaks, largely owing to a surge in global reserves boosted by robust US shale production.Teo said a surprisingly robust jobs report in the United States was also supporting prices as it heralds stronger demand.The Labor Department on Friday reported that the world´s biggest economy added 257,000 jobs in January and revised upward already healthy growth in the previous two months.The unemployment rate edged up to 5.7 percent from 5.6 percent, but that was in part because more people were actively seeking jobs. (AFP)                        










",2/9/2015,oil prices extend gai,business,"['London', 'North', 'American', 'US', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'Brent', 'North', 'Sea', 'London', 'WTI', 'Brent', 'Nicholas', 'Teo', 'CMC', 'Markets', 'Singapore', 'United', 'States', 'US', 'Baker', 'Hughes', 'Inc', 'United', 'States', 'Bloomberg', 'News', 'BP', 'BG', 'Group', 'US', 'Teo', 'United', 'States', 'Labor', 'Department', 'AFP']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
29,"Singapore: Oil prices fell in Asia on Tuesday after the International Energy Agency (IEA) predicted that global oil prices will recover only partially over the next five years, analysts said.US benchmark West Texas Intermediate (WTI) for March delivery slipped 74 cents to $52.12, while Brent crude for March eased 77 cents to $57.57 in afternoon trade. Citing a major shakeup in the oil markets, the IEA said in its five-year forecast that prices will recover from current levels of around $50-60 per barrel but remain considerably below the more than $100 price tags reached the slump began in June.""The global oil market looks set to begin a new chapter of its history, with markedly changing demand dynamics, sweeping shifts in crude trade and product supply, and dramatically different roles for OPEC and non-OPEC producers in regulating upstream supply,"" the IEA said.It added that it sees market rebalancing occurring ""relatively swiftly"", with increases in inventories halting mid-year and the market tightening.""This morning´s slight dip is likely due to the IEA report that predicts only a slow recovery for oil prices. However this is only in the short term as the market fundamentals have not changed,"" said Shailaja Nair, associate editorial director at energy information provider Platts.Prices have plunged from their mid-2014 peaks largely owing to a surge in global reserves boosted by robust US shale production and weak global demand. (AFP)                        










",2/10/2015,oil prices fall as iea predicts weak rebound,business,"['Singapore', 'Asia', 'International', 'Energy', 'Agency', 'IEA', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'WTI', 'Brent', 'IEA', 'OPEC', 'OPEC', 'IEA', 'IEA', 'Shailaja', 'Nair', 'Platts', 'US', 'AFP']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG']"
30,"MUZAFFARABAD: The Intra-Kashmir trade service will resume tonight after six days of its suspension at the Chakothi crossing point, Geo News reported on Wednesday.The trade service was suspended after authorities in Indian occupied Kashmir leveled allegations of smuggling.It was suspended when a truck from Azad Kashmir was stopped by Indian authorities allegedly said to be carrying contraband.According to Director General (DG) Azad Kashmir Trade and Travel Authority (TATA) Brigadier (R)Imtiaz Wayen, 50 trucks from AJK and 21 from IoK will return tonight.On Sunday in an interview with AFP, Basharat Iqbal, trade facilitation officer on the Pakistani side of the border said: “We were informed by the Indian authorities on Friday evening that they have stopped 22 Pakistani trucks which crossed the Line of Control (LOC) earlier that day.""""They told us that they had discovered 12 kilograms (26 pounds) of opium from a truck carrying oranges and were taking an action against the driver. After the incident, we also held 50 Indian trucks on Pakistani Kashmir side, because traffic crosses the border simultaneously,"" said Iqbal.Imtiaz Wayen, director-general of Pakistani Kashmir´s trade and travel authority, said India was not entitled to stop Pakistani drivers on grounds of smuggling.""According to our agreement, if they find any banned item in our trucks they are bound to hand over that item and the relevant truck driver to us for further action,"" he said.                        










",2/11/2015,intra kashmir trade resumes after six day,business,"['MUZAFFARABAD', 'Intra', '-', 'Kashmir', 'Chakothi', 'Geo', 'News', 'Indian', 'Kashmir', 'Azad', 'Kashmir', 'Indian', 'DG', 'Azad', 'Kashmir', 'Trade', 'and', 'Travel', 'Authority', 'TATA', 'R', 'Imtiaz', 'Wayen', 'AJK', 'IoK', 'AFP', 'Basharat', 'Iqbal', 'Pakistani', 'Indian', 'Pakistani', 'Line', 'of', 'Control', 'LOC', 'Indian', 'Pakistani', 'Kashmir', 'Iqbal', 'Imtiaz', 'Wayen', 'Pakistani', 'Kashmir´s', 'India', 'Pakistani']","['I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC']"
31,"ISLAMABAD: Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif on Wednesday called for speedy implementation of Turkmenistan-Afghanistan-Pakistan-India (TAPI) gas pipeline project terming it critical for the regional countries.The meeting in Islamabad included Petroleum Ministers of Turkmenistan, Afghanistan and India as well as Pakistan’s Minister for Petroleum and Natural Resources Shahid Khaqan Abbasi.The PM said that Pakistan would play a positive role for the early progress on TAPI and any delay would add heavily to the cost.He went on to say that Pakistan was facing an acute shortage of gas and that this project would help Pakistan overcome the crisis. On February 6, Minister of State for Petroleum and Natural Resources Jam Kamal said that Pakistan would host technical group meetings of the TAPI project here during this month. All the countries under TAPI would participate in the meetings as the gas sales and purchase agreement had already been signed. He also said that project development was in progress while consultants were engaged in carrying out feasibility study and design.  










",2/11/2015,pakistan wants early implementation of tapi project ,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Nawaz', 'Sharif', 'Turkmenistan', '-', 'Afghanistan', '-', 'Pakistan', '-', 'India', 'TAPI', 'Islamabad', 'Petroleum', 'Turkmenistan', 'Afghanistan', 'India', 'Pakistans', 'Petroleum', 'and', 'Natural', 'Resources', 'Shahid', 'Khaqan', 'Abbasi', 'Pakistan', 'TAPI', 'Pakistan', 'Pakistan', 'Petroleum', 'and', 'Natural', 'Resources', 'Jam', 'Kamal', 'Pakistan', 'TAPI', 'TAPI']","['I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
32,"SYDNEY: Cricket fever has gripped Australia with the World Cup just days away. Fans from around the world have thronged to the country and hotels are capitalising. Prices of rooms have almost doubled to 300 dollars and hotels are experiencing full bookings. Experts estimate that during the mega event Australia will generate 1.5 million US dollars just from hotel bookings. If the cost of internal air travel, taxis and tickets is taken into consideration, Australia stands to generate two million US dollars during the World Cup.  










",2/11/2015,hotel prices skyrocket in australia ahead of world cu,business,"['Cricket', 'Australia', 'World', 'Cup', 'Australia', 'US', 'Australia', 'US', 'World', 'Cup']","['I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC']"
33,"Karachi: Microsoft Devices Pakistan announced the availability of Nokia 215 Dual SIM, its most affordable Internet-ready phone, in the country. The Nokia 215 Dual SIM is designed to connect and introduce first-time mobile phone buyers to the Internet and new digital experiences. The Nokia 215 Dual SIM will expand the reach of Microsoft services at more affordable prices.Nokia 215 Dual SIM will allow more people to access popular Web content and digital services, and enable them to enjoy online experiences via Opera Mini browser, Bing search, MSN Weather, Twitter and Facebook. People can stay in touch with friends and family using Facebook and Messenger with instant notifications. With SLAM, people can share content between devices and make hands-free calls using Bluetooth 3.0.With a fresh design, durable quality and outstanding battery life, this entry-level mobile phone is an owner’s delight. It has all the essentials for a mobile-first world such as built-in torchlight, up to 20 hours of talk-time, outstanding battery life (up to 21 days for the Dual SIM), MP3 playback of up to 50 hours, FM radio playback of up to 45 hours and a VGA camera.Commenting at the launch of Nokia 215 Dual SIM, Kamran Khan, Country General Manager, Microsoft Mobile Devices Pakistan said: “With our ultra-affordable mobile phones and digital services, we see an inspiring opportunity to connect the next billion people to the Internet for the first time. The Nokia 215 Dual SIM is perfect for people looking for their first mobile device, or those wanting to upgrade to enjoy affordable digital and social media services, like Facebook and Messenger.”The Nokia 215 Dual SIM comes in Bright Green, Black and White, and will be available for an estimated retail price of PKR 4,100/-.                        










",2/12/2015,nokia 215 dual sim launched in paki,business,"['Karachi', 'Microsoft', 'Devices', 'Pakistan', 'Nokia', 'Dual', 'SIM', 'Internet', 'Nokia', 'Dual', 'SIM', 'Nokia', 'Dual', 'SIM', 'Microsoft', 'Nokia', 'Dual', 'SIM', 'Opera', 'Mini', 'Bing', 'MSN', 'Bluetooth', '3', '.', '0', 'Dual', 'SIM', 'MP3', 'FM', 'VGA', 'Nokia', 'Dual', 'SIM', 'Kamran', 'Khan', 'Microsoft', 'Mobile', 'Devices', 'Pakistan', 'Nokia', 'Dual', 'SIM', 'Facebook', 'Messenger', 'Nokia', 'Dual', 'SIM', 'Bright', 'Green', 'Black', 'White']","['I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC']"
34,"ISLAMABAD: Federal Finance Minister Ishaq Dar on Thursday said that only companies will be issued National Tax Numbers (NTN) from now onwards while the Computerised National Identity Card (CNIC) numbers will be treated as tax numbers for individuals.While addressing the National Assembly today, Dar said that a shortfall of Rs 196 billion in revenue collection is expected this year and the government has taken measures to reduce it by Rs 46 billion by imposing additional tax.The minister added that the increase in GST on petroleum products and a change in other taxes was imperative to meet various needs including release of funds to the provinces from the devisable pool. He also said that expenditures in the wake of Zarb-e-Azb operation cannot be ignored, as well as factors such as debt servicing and payment of salaries.He went on to say that the government has lowered the revenue collection target to Rs. 2691 billion from Rs. 2810 billion. 










",2/12/2015,cnic number now tax number only companies allowed ntn dar,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Federal', 'Ishaq', 'Dar', 'National', 'NTN', 'Computerised', 'National', 'Card', 'CNIC', 'National', 'Assembly', 'Dar', 'Zarb', '-', 'e', '-', 'Azb']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
35,"ISLAMABAD: Government has put in place new taxes of Rs4 billion while regulatory duty on 314 luxury items has been ratcheted up to 10 percent.The decision comes weeks after the central bank suggested in its monetary policy report that it would be challenging for the government to meet the revenue targets for the current fiscal year.According to the notification of the Federal Board of Revenue (FBR), the Federal Board of Revenue (FBR) has also raised regulatory duty on furnace oil, scraped metal, imported make-up and electronic appliances.Regulatory duty on imported chocolates has been increased by 10 percent and on electronic goods to 5 percent. The duty has been raised from 5 to 10 percent on scraped metal, imported makeup.The above decisions were made during the last meeting of the Economic Coordination Committee (ECC). 










",2/12/2015,govt imposes new taxes of rs4 billi,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Rs4', 'Federal', 'Board', 'of', 'Revenue', 'FBR', 'Federal', 'Board', 'of', 'Revenue', 'FBR', 'Economic', 'Coordination', 'Committee', 'ECC']","['I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
36,"Singapore: Oil prices edged higher in Asia Thursday but gains were capped owing to concerns about surging stockpiles in the United States, the world´s top consumer, analysts said. US benchmark West Texas Intermediate for March delivery rose 69 cents to $49.53 while Brent crude for March gained 34 cents to $55.00 in afternoon trade.""There is some optimism in the market at the moment, but the fundamentals have not changed,"" Michael McCarthy, chief market strategist at CMC Markets in Sydney, told AFP. ""The increased US stockpiles adds to the worry about ample global supply, which is the main cause for the current bearish market,"" he added. The US Department of Energy reported on Wednesday that commercial crude reserves rose 4.9 million barrels in the week ending February 6.Stockpiles were ""at the highest level for this time of year in at least the last 80 years"", the agency added.Oil prices have been under pressure for months, plunging about 60 percent to just over $40 a barrel between June and the end of January.However, they have recovered slightly in recent weeks as the number of drilling rigs has fallen and oil companies have trimmed some investment.Investors are also monitoring talks on Greece´s demands to renegotiate its international bailout as the risk of a debt default looms. A meeting between Finance Minister Yaris Varoufakis and his counterparts from the eurozone late Wednesday broke up without agreement, with deliberations now set to go down to the wire next week. ""We expect price action to remain choppy as markets await for direction,"" said Singapore´s United Overseas Bank. (AFP)                        










",2/12/2015,oil prices rise in asian trad,business,"['Singapore', 'Asia', 'United', 'States', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'Brent', 'Michael', 'McCarthy', 'CMC', 'Markets', 'Sydney', 'AFP', 'US', 'US', 'Department', 'of', 'Energy', 'Greece´s', 'Yaris', 'Varoufakis', 'eurozone', 'Singapore´s', 'United', 'Overseas', 'Bank', 'AFP']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
37,"London: World oil prices rose Friday, extending solid gains in the previous session in response to reports that leading petroleum producers are curtailing investment.US benchmark West Texas Intermediate (WTI) for March delivery added 75 cents to $51.96 a barrel compared with Thursday´s close.Brent North Sea crude for April leapt $1.02 to $60.30 a barrel in London afternoon trade -- the first time this year above $60.Crude futures had rallied by almost $2.50 on Thursday on reports of falling investment in the oil sector.Daniel Ang, investment analyst at Phillip Futures in Singapore, said dealers are wary about the impact of such cuts in the immediate term. ""We will continue to see range-bound trading in the immediate term with little change to fundamentals,"" Ang told AFP. ""The main thing is crude production. As long as production levels don´t go down for now, it is hard to see a reversal of low oil prices,"" he said.""Markets seem to be ready for prices to go up again. They are just waiting for a sign that production will be significantly cut."" A US stockpiles report Wednesday showing crude reserves standing at an 80-year high for this time of the year has exacerbated concerns about a global supply glut. Oil prices have been under pressure for months, plunging about 60 percent to just over $40 a barrel between June and the end of January.However, they have recovered slightly in recent weeks as the number of drilling rigs has fallen and oil companies such as Total and Royal Dutch Shell trimmed some investment. (AFP)                        










",2/13/2015,oil prices extend gai,business,"['London', 'World', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'WTI', 'Brent', 'North', 'Sea', 'London', 'Daniel', 'Ang', 'Phillip', 'Futures', 'Singapore', 'Ang', 'AFP', 'US', 'Total', 'Royal', 'Dutch', 'Shell', 'AFP']","['I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
38,"KARACHI: The price of furnace oil used in the production of electricity in Pakistan has increased by about Rs 2000 per tonne to reach Rs 37400 per tonne.A rise in global crude oil prices has affected the otherwise consistently falling price of furnace oil. According to experts, the constant falling price of furnace oil during October to December last year attributed to the reduction of cost of electricity production by Rs 3. The relief is being passed on to consumers gradually by the government. 










",2/16/2015,furnace oil price rises by about rs 2000 per ,business,"['KARACHI', 'Pakistan']","['I-ORG', 'I-LOC']"
39,"ISLAMABAD: The National Electric Power Regulatory Authority (NEPRA) issued a notification on Tuesday regarding provision of relief of Rs 3.24 per unit to power consumers.According to the notification, the regulatory authority decided the reduction after a review of the fuel price adjustment for December 2014.The relief would be provided to all consumers except for those belonging to K-Electric. 










",2/17/2015,nepra notifies relief of rs 3.24 per unit for consumer,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'National', 'Electric', 'Power', 'Regulatory', 'Authority', 'NEPRA', 'K', '-', 'Electric']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
40,"CAIRO/ISLAMABAD: State-run Gulf energy company Qatargas is in the final stages of talks on a deal to supply Pakistan with 3 million tonnes of liquefied natural gas (LNG) annually for 15 years, industry sources in Doha told Reuters on Wednesday.The deal would help the country tackle serious energy shortages and power cuts which can last up to 20 hours a day. Nearly half the country’s electricity is generated by gas and its output of 4.1 billion cubic feet per day is well short of demand for as much as 6 billion, depending on the time of year.One source said the deal would be signed in weeks, while a second said the first shipment would be received by March.An official at the Ministry of Water and Power confirmed an LNG deal was planned but declined to give details. No-one at Qatargas, the world´s largest LNG producer, was available to comment.Pakistan State Oil (PSO) said payments to Qatar would be guaranteed by the government so any cash flow problems at PSO would not affect the Qatargas deal.                        










",2/18/2015,qatargas pakistan close to 15 year lng supply d,business,"['CAIRO', 'ISLAMABAD', 'State', 'Gulf', 'Qatargas', 'Pakistan', 'LNG', 'Doha', 'Reuters', 'Ministry', 'of', 'Water', 'and', 'Power', 'LNG', 'Qatargas', 'LNG', 'Pakistan', 'State', 'Oil', 'PSO', 'Qatar', 'PSO', 'Qatargas']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
41,"ISLAMABAD: Pakistan’s Finance Minister Ishaq Dar said  the cost of ongoing Operation Zarb-e-Azb in North Waziristan may exceed $1.3 billion. Dar met with US Senate Armed Services Committee member, Jack Reed and Ambassador Richard Olson and informed them that the Pakistani government had already spent $400 million on the operation and IDPs. During the meeting the finance minister said the operation had the full support of political parties, armed forces and civil society in the country.  Dar added that Pakistani had suffered economically due to the exodus of people from the tribal areas owing to the operation. Senator Jack Reed said it was essential that the global community helped Pakistan in its fight against terrorism.  










",2/19/2015,operation zarb e azb may cost over 1.3 billion dar,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Pakistans', 'Ishaq', 'Dar', 'Zarb', '-', 'e', '-', 'Azb', 'North', 'Waziristan', 'Dar', 'US', 'Senate', 'Armed', 'Services', 'Committee', 'Jack', 'Reed', 'Richard', 'Olson', 'Pakistani', 'IDPs', 'Dar', 'Pakistani', 'Jack', 'Reed', 'Pakistan']","['I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-PER', 'I-MISC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC']"
42,"New York: Oil prices fell on Wednesday before the release of a report on US crude inventories as traders kept an eye on unrest in crude exporter Libya.US benchmark West Texas Intermediate for delivery in March shed $1.39 to $52.14 a barrel compared with Tuesday´s close.European benchmark Brent oil for April delivery slid $2.00 to $60.53 a barrel in London.The US Department of Energy will release its weekly stockpiles report on Thursday with many analysts expecting another large rise in stocks.Last week´s report showed that US crude inventories reached their highest levels on record for this time of the year.""The market had a very nice rebound from the $44-45 low it made a little while back,"" said Kyle Cooper, analyst at IAF Advisors in Houston.""But the fundamentals are still on the downside, and expectations are for a crude oil build"" on Thursday.""I don´t think the production growth is going to slow in the next couple of months.""Although leading producers like Chevron and ConocoPhillips have slashed capital budgets in light of the more than 50 percent plunge in global crude prices, the cuts are not expected to significantly affect short-term production levels.Traders were also keeping an eye on developments in north African crude oil producer Libya.Infighting and sabotage in Libya has reduced output to 150,000 barrels a day, down from a high of almost 1.5 million barrels per day, according to analysts. (AFP)                        










",2/19/2015,oil prices fall on eve of us inventory d,business,"['New', 'York', 'US', 'Libya', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'European', 'Brent', 'London', 'US', 'Department', 'of', 'Energy', 'US', 'Kyle', 'Cooper', 'IAF', 'Advisors', 'Houston', 'Chevron', 'ConocoPhillips', 'African', 'Libya', 'Libya', 'AFP']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG']"
43,"SAN FRANCISCO: Apple Inc aims to begin producing electric vehicles as early as 2020, Bloomberg reported.The report cited people with knowledge of the matter as saying, a seemingly aggressive target for a mobile devices maker with little experience in car manufacture.The iPhone maker is pushing its ""car team"" of about 200 people to meet that goal.But Apple may decide to scrap its car-making effort, or delay it, if executives grew unhappy with its progress, the news agency said. 










",2/20/2015,apple to begin manufacturing electric vehicles as early as 2020,business,"['SAN', 'FRANCISCO', 'Apple', 'Inc', 'Bloomberg', 'iPhone', 'Apple']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
44,"New York: New York oil prices fell in late trade Friday, with the WTI contract breaking away from a stable trade in London to fall near the $50 dollar line.West Texas Intermediate for March delivery settled at the official close at $50.32 a barrel, down 82 cents from Thursday, as the contract expired. WTI then continued to fall further in late trade, dropping below $50.In London, Brent crude for April delivery was flat at $60.22 a barrel, one cent higher from a day earlier.US and Canadian output continued to rise despite the weak market, adding to the gap between the two key benchmarks.""Still-rising US production and climbing inventories remain the more relevant fundamental story,"" said Timothy Evans of Citi Futures.Analysts at JPMorgan said reports of production and export drops in the Middle East and North Africa helped hold up London prices.""An additional support also comes from higher crude demand in Europe from strong refinery margins and US refinery maintenance allowing refiners elsewhere to fill the product supply gap,"" they said.""We continue to expect that crude markets will come under pressure in the short term, however, fundamentals point to stress on Brent-related crude outweighing that on WTI.""More broadly, they said they foresee overall demand will decline as refineries adjust to different conditions, further pressing downward on prices.""Assuming that Brent markets witness a reversal of the supply losses that have tightened them significantly in recent weeks, then we would expect weaker Brent cash differentials and structure to erode the support for Brent crude against other benchmarks, notably WTI."" (AFP)                        










",2/21/2015,oil prices fall in new yor,business,"['New', 'York', 'New', 'York', 'WTI', 'London', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'WTI', 'London', 'Brent', 'US', 'Canadian', 'US', 'Timothy', 'Evans', 'Citi', 'Futures', 'JPMorgan', 'Middle', 'East', 'North', 'Africa', 'London', 'Europe', 'US', 'Brent', '-', 'WTI', 'Brent', 'Brent', 'Brent', 'WTI', 'AFP']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
45,"ISLAMABAD: Minister for Petroleum Shahid Khaqan Abbasi on Monday said the government will begin importing Liquefied Natural Gas (LNG) from March 31.Talking to Geo News, the Petroleum Minister said initially 300 MMCFD (million cubic feet per day) of LNG will be imported. After six months the import volume will be increased to 400 MMCFD, he added.Shahid Khaqan Abbasi informed that Pakistan’s current consumer demand for LNG stands at 600 MMCFD.He said that in the initial phase, the Finance Ministry will foot the LNG import bill from subsidy allocated for the power sector.The Minister said the electricity generation from LNG will cost Pakistan less compared to the power production from diesel.He, however, said that the price for LNG has not yet been determined. 










",2/23/2015,lng import to begin from march 31 abbasi,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Petroleum', 'Shahid', 'Khaqan', 'Abbasi', 'Liquefied', 'Natural', 'Gas', 'LNG', 'Geo', 'News', 'Petroleum', 'LNG', 'Shahid', 'Khaqan', 'Abbasi', 'Pakistans', 'LNG', 'Finance', 'Ministry', 'LNG', 'LNG', 'Pakistan', 'LNG']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC']"
46,"KARACHI: The price of sugar decreased by 50 paisas in the wholesale market and is now being sold at Rs 49 per kilo. According to sources in the wholesale market, the price decrease took place due to an increase in the supply of sugar. The price decrease is also being experienced at the retail level where sugar is being sold at Rs 52 which is an Rs 1-2 decrease.  










",2/23/2015,price of sugar decreases in karachi,business,['KARACHI'],['I-ORG']
47,"London: Oil prices rebounded slightly Tuesday after recent sharp losses caused by an oversupplied market.US benchmark West Texas Intermediate (WTI) for April delivery rose 39 cents to $49.84 a barrel.Brent North Sea crude for April climbed 51 cents to stand at $59.41 a barrel in London afternoon deals.WTI shed $1.36 in New York and Brent lost $1.32 on Monday, building on heavy losses last Friday, as US crude stockpiles linger at historic levels, contributing to a global oversupply.A closely watched report on US weekly crude stockpiles is next due on Wednesday, with a Bloomberg News survey saying inventories are expected to have risen by 3.75 million barrels.US oil stockpiles are already at their highest level on record at this time of year.""The expectation of further rising US crude oil stocks is pressuring prices,"" said Commerzbank analysts in a note to clients.Globally, crude supplies are also being boosted after oilfields in eastern Libya resumed pumping to the port of Hariga after a pipeline was repaired, and oil producer Oman plans to ramp up output to 980,000 barrels a day this year.""The partial return of supply from Libya is weighing on the Brent price despite its sustainability being anything but certain,"" said Commerzbank.Crude prices lost about 60 percent of their value to about $40 between June and late January owing to an oversupply in world markets, a weak global economy and a strong dollar.Prices have risen above multi-year lows following a slowdown in US oil drilling activities, but analysts say volatility is likely to continue for some time.""It is apparent by now that drilling in the US will slow, global production growth is expected to be lower, and demand, at least in the US, is reacting positively to lower prices,"" British bank Barclays said in a report.""In short, the market is forecast to remain oversupplied for most of 2015, but expectations beyond that are for more balanced fundamentals."" (AFP)                        










",2/24/2015,oil prices rebound slightly,business,"['London', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'WTI', 'Brent', 'North', 'Sea', 'London', 'WTI', 'New', 'York', 'Brent', 'US', 'US', 'Bloomberg', 'News', 'US', 'US', 'Commerzbank', 'Libya', 'Hariga', 'Oman', 'Libya', 'Brent', 'Commerzbank', 'US', 'US', 'US', 'British', 'Barclays']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG']"
48,"TOKYO: Tokyo stocks opened flat on Tuesday after recent advances to 15-year highs as caution over a Greek debt deal grew.The Nikkei 225 index at the Tokyo Stock Exchange was up 1.47 points, or 0.01 percent, at 18,468.39 at the start.The euro remained under pressure as traders waited to see if Greece could complete the agreement reached last week with eurozone partners on its bailout programme.Athens has delayed sending a list of reforms to its international lenders aimed at obtaining a four-month extension of its bailout.The euro bought $1.1332 and 134.73 yen early Tuesday, compared with $1.1337 and 134.63 yen in New York Monday afternoon.The dollar was at 118.87 yen against 118.76 yen in US trade. Among individual stocks, Hitachi eased 0.20 percent to 833.0 yen in early trade after media reports that the Japanese firm reached a basic accord with Italian aerospace and defence giant Finmeccanica to buy its rail business for 250 billion yen ($2.1 billion).On Wall Street on Monday, the Dow Jones Industrial Average declined 0.13 percent following lacklustre housing data on the eve of congressional testimony by Federal Reserve chair Janet Yellen 










",2/24/2015,tokyo stocks open f,business,"['TOKYO', 'Tokyo', 'Greek', 'Nikkei', '225', 'Tokyo', 'Stock', 'Exchange', 'Greece', 'eurozone', 'Athens', 'New', 'York', 'US', 'Hitachi', 'Japanese', 'Italian', 'Finmeccanica', 'Wall', 'Street', 'Dow', 'Jones', 'Federal', 'Reserve', 'Janet', 'Yellen']","['I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER']"
49,"ISLAMABAD: All the petroleum products except diesel are likely to be increased from March 01, Geo News reported.Sources said Oil and Gas Regulatory Authority (OGRA) has prepared summary for hike in the POL product prices on the basis of 27 per cent General Sales Tax (GST) and moved it to Ministry for Petroleum.Sources said OGRA has proposed Rs5.59/litre hike for petrol, Rs7.32 Kerosene oil, Rs12.62 HOBC and Light Diesel Rs5.50 per litre.The authority has also suggested Rs5.49/litre decrease in the diesel prices.The Ministry for Petroleum will forward the summary to the Finance Ministry for a final go-ahead.                        










",2/26/2015,pol prices likely to go up from march 1,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Geo', 'News', 'Oil', 'and', 'Gas', 'Regulatory', 'Authority', 'OGRA', 'POL', 'General', 'Tax', 'GST', 'Ministry', 'for', 'Petroleum', 'OGRA', 'Kerosene', 'HOBC', 'Light', 'Diesel', 'Ministry', 'for', 'Petroleum', 'Finance', 'Ministry']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
50,"ISLAMABAD: Ambassador of Tajikistan Sher Ali Jononov on Friday said that his country was preparing to export sizeable quantity of electricity to Pakistan to lessen the intensity of the energy crisis which has compromised economic growth. The KASA 1000 project is among the major electricity transfer projects in the region, based on which 1,300 megawatts of electricity from Kazakhstan and Tajikistan is expected to be transferred to Afghanistan and Pakistan.He said that Tajikistan wished to enhance bilateral trade with Pakistan and invited the business community to visit his country to explore investment opportunities and organise trade exhibitions. He added that the energy sector of Tajikistan had been showing sustainable growth for the last 15 years transforming the country into the world’s third largest producer of hydroelectric power after the US and Russia. Jononov went on to say that hydroelectric generation accounted for 76 percent of the total energy output of the country and the total cost of the project which would lighten Pakistan through Tajik electricity will be financed by the World Bank, ADB, Islamic Development Bank and other donors.He also said that this project would not only alleviate electricity shortages in Pakistan but would also replace fuel based electricity generation for Afghanistan and Pakistan, adding that it would also establish Afghanistan as a viable transit country and offer transmission capacity for other countries during the off peak season.He further said that it would also create a viable governance mechanism to build confidence among neighbours as major share of the export will be used by Pakistan and approximately 300 MW will be utilised by Afghanistan. 










",2/27/2015,tajikistan to help pakistan overcome energy crisis through kasa 1000 proj,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Tajikistan', 'Sher', 'Ali', 'Jononov', 'Pakistan', 'KASA', 'Kazakhstan', 'Tajikistan', 'Afghanistan', 'Pakistan', 'Tajikistan', 'Pakistan', 'Tajikistan', 'US', 'Russia', 'Jononov', 'Pakistan', 'Tajik', 'World', 'Bank', 'ADB', 'Islamic', 'Development', 'Bank', 'Pakistan', 'Afghanistan', 'Pakistan', 'Afghanistan', 'Pakistan', 'Afghanistan']","['I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
51,"London: Global oil prices fell Monday, after bumper gains before the weekend, as many traders took profits and eyed plentiful world crude supplies, analysts said. European benchmark Brent North Sea crude for April delivery dropped $1.26 to $61.32 a barrel in London early afternoon deals.New York´s West Texas Intermediate (WTI) for April shed 90 cents to $48.86 a barrel.Crude futures had rebounded sharply Friday at the end of a volatile trading week. WTI had advanced $1.59 while Brent gained a hefty $2.53.""Oil prices came under renewed pressure,"" said Sucden analyst Myrto Sokou on Monday.""Crude oil inventories continue to remain at fairly high levels following ongoing builds of crude stocks last week.""Oil has lost about 50 percent of its value since June, largely due to a global supply glut partially caused by surging US shale production.""Although there is still a global supply glut, oil prices are on a general increasing trend especially with the falling rig count numbers indicating that US shale is responding to low prices,"" Ken Hasegawa, energy trading manager at Newedge Group in Tokyo, told AFP. The weekly Baker Hughes US drilling rig count showed the number of rigs in operation fell by 33 to 986 in the week to February 27. The count is down 39 percent since October, according to Bloomberg News. Analysts said dealers will next be scrutinising a slew of US economic data to be released later Monday for clues on demand prospects in the world´s biggest crude consumer.  (AFP)                        










",3/2/2015,oil market recoils on oversupply,business,"['London', 'European', 'Brent', 'North', 'Sea', 'London', 'New', 'York´s', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'WTI', 'WTI', 'Brent', 'Sucden', 'Myrto', 'Sokou', 'US', 'US', 'Ken', 'Hasegawa', 'Newedge', 'Group', 'Tokyo', 'AFP', 'Baker', 'Hughes', 'US', 'Bloomberg', 'News', 'US', 'AFP']","['I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG']"
52,"HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks rose 0.70 percent in the first few minutes of trade Monday after China´s central bank at the weekend cut interest rates for the second time since November.The benchmark Hang Seng Index added 173.47 points to 24,996.76. 










",3/2/2015,hong kong stocks open 0.70 percent higher,business,"['Hong', 'Kong', 'China´s', 'Hang', 'Seng']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC']"
53,"NEW YORK: Billionaire philanthropist Bill Gates kept his spot as the world’s richest man, a rank he has held for 16 of the past 21 years, Forbes magazine said Monday.The Microsoft co-founder’s fortune increased $3.2 billion since last year to $79.2 billion, the business magazine said, despite a $1.5 billion gift of Microsoft shares to the Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation in November.Mexican telecom tycoon Carlos Slim held onto second place thanks to his $77.1 billion, ahead of American investor Warren Buffett, with $72.7 billion. The so-called Oracle of Omaha was the biggest gainer of the Forbes list this year, up $14.5 billion from last year riding on the rising share price of his Berkshire Hathaway.In fourth was Amancio Ortega, founder of the Inditex fashion group that includes Zara clothing retail shops. He counts a fortune of $64.5 billion.Facebook co-founder Mark Zuckerberg jumped five spots to land in number 16, the first time he made it within the exclusive circle of the world´s 20 richest people.Jack Ma, whose Alibaba online marketplace made the biggest global IPO ever last year, was ranked among the world´s 50 richest people, along with two other Chinese nationals.The number of billionaires is growing steadily, breaking an all-time record this year, with 1,826 — up from 1,645 last year.The rise of the dollar against the euro, along with plunging oil prices, had a significant impact on this year’s list.                        










",3/3/2015,bill gates still the richest man in the world,business,"['NEW', 'Bill', 'Gates', 'Forbes', 'Microsoft', 'Microsoft', 'Bill', '&', 'Melinda', 'Gates', 'Foundation', 'Mexican', 'Carlos', 'Slim', 'American', 'Warren', 'Buffett', 'Oracle', 'of', 'Omaha', 'Forbes', 'Berkshire', 'Hathaway', 'Amancio', 'Ortega', 'Inditex', 'Zara', 'Facebook', 'Mark', 'Zuckerberg', 'Jack', 'Ma', 'Alibaba', 'Chinese']","['I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-MISC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC']"
54,"ISLAMABAD: Federal Minister for Water and Power Khawaja Asif on Wednesday said that despite the expiry of an agreement with the K-Electric, power is being supplied to it keeping in view the interest of people of the metropolis.Speaking to media representatives, he said that K-Electric has the capacity to generate sufficient power to meet the requirements of Karachi. However, it gets 650 MW of subsidised electricity from the national grid, he added. Asif said the issue will be reviewed in the new contract agreement with the K-Electric.The minister said the duration of loadshedding has been reduced across the country as compared to the previous year. Industries are being provided with uninterrupted electricity now, he added.To a question about the funding of Diamer Basha Dam, the power minister said the government will start construction on the project from its own resources. When asked about violations of Indus Water Treaty by India, Khawaja Asif said Pakistan is vigilant to the situation and will raise the matter at an appropriate forum in case of any violation.                        










",3/4/2015,pact with k electric expired govt not bound to provide power asif,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'Federal', 'Water', 'and', 'Power', 'Khawaja', 'Asif', 'K', '-', 'Electric', 'K', '-', 'Electric', 'Karachi', 'Asif', 'K', '-', 'Electric', 'Diamer', 'Basha', 'Dam', 'Indus', 'Water', 'India', 'Khawaja', 'Asif', 'Pakistan']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC']"
55,"London: Oil prices rose on Friday as dealers awaited US jobs data and focused on increasing tensions in the Middle East and Ukraine.US benchmark West Texas Intermediate for delivery in April added 14 cents to $50.90 a barrel.Brent North Sea crude for April gained 56 cents to stand at $61.04 a barrel around midday in London.Investors awaited the release Friday of US non-farm payrolls data that, if strong enough, could support a Federal Reserve interest rate increase in the world´s biggest consumer of crude.Analysts expect growth of 240,000 jobs in February and a fall in the unemployment rate to 5.6 percent from 5.7 percent.""Crude oil prices climbed higher... ahead of the release of the US employment data which will set the tone for today´s trading session,"" said Myrto Sokou, senior research analyst at Sucden brokers.Michael McCarthy, chief market strategist at CMC Markets in Sydney, told AFP that traders were ""seeing a lot of upside potential, possibly based on tensions in the Middle East and Ukraine.""""Somehow, we are seeing investors looking away from the huge build in US (crude oil) inventories this week,"" he added.Libya´s National Oil Corporation declared force majeure Wednesday at 11 oil fields after attacks by militants.The OPEC member country has been battling the rise of militias seeking control of its cities and oil wealth since the killing of dictator Moamer Kadhafi in 2011.Unabated fighting has seen its output reduced from a high of almost 1.5 million barrels a day to 150,000, according to analysts.In Ukraine, investors are closely watching latest efforts to prop up a ceasefire in the country´s eastern region, currently controlled by pro-Russia rebels.The 10-month conflict in the country -- a key conduit for Russian energy exports to Europe -- is seen as Europe´s worse since the war in the Balkans in the 1990s.Data on Wednesday meanwhile showed a 10.3 million barrels surge in US crude reserves in the week to February 27, which dampened expectations of robust demand in the world´s biggest economy. (AFP)                        










",3/6/2015,oil prices rise before us jobs d,business,"['London', 'US', 'Middle', 'East', 'Ukraine', 'US', 'West', 'Texas', 'Intermediate', 'Brent', 'North', 'Sea', 'London', 'US', 'Federal', 'Reserve', 'US', 'Myrto', 'Sokou', 'Sucden', 'Michael', 'McCarthy', 'CMC', 'Markets', 'Sydney', 'AFP', 'Middle', 'East', 'Ukraine', 'US', 'Libya´s', 'National', 'Oil', 'Corporation', 'OPEC', 'Moamer', 'Kadhafi', 'Ukraine', '-', 'Russia', 'Russian', 'Europe', 'Europe´s', 'Balkans', 'US']","['I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
56,"DUBAI: Bahria Town and K-Electric signed an agreement on Saturday, which will add 500MW of electricity supply for Karachi. According to the deal inked in UAE, KElectric will set up one coal based and one liquefied natural gas (LNG) based power plant in the metropolis and will supply uninterrupted power to Bahria Town Karachi.Speaking exclusively to Geo.tv from UAE, K-Electric’s spokesperson Usama Qureshi confirmed that two agreements have been signed, which include setting up of a 300MW coal powered plant and a 200MW LNG powered plant, while the second agreement pertains to supplying uninterrupted power to Bahria Town Karachi. Speaking on the occasion Ex-Chairman & Founder of Bahria Town Malik Riaz said, “For the people of Karachi, LNG and coal powered plants will be setup and Karachi Bahria Town will receive uninterrupted power supply.” 










",3/7/2015,bahria town kelectric ink agreement on power plants for karachi,business,"['Bahria', 'Town', 'K', '-', 'Electric', 'Karachi', 'UAE', 'KElectric', 'LNG', 'Bahria', 'Town', 'Karachi', 'Geo', 'UAE', 'K', '-', 'Electrics', 'Usama', 'Qureshi', 'LNG', 'Bahria', 'Town', 'Karachi', 'Bahria', 'Town', 'Malik', 'Riaz', 'Karachi', 'LNG', 'Karachi', 'Bahria', 'Town']","['I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-MISC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
57,"ISLAMABAD: International Monetary Fund (IMF) Director for Middle East and Central Asia, Masood Ahmed said the economic survey of Pakistan is conducted keeping in mind the security situation in the country. Speaking at a seminar here, Ahmed said the IMF was aware that billions spent on security were putting pressure on Pakistan’s economy. He added the IMF has issued directives to Pakistan to decrease expenses and to focus on health and education in the budget. The IMF has also directed Pakistan to take necessary measures to increase tax revenue.  










",3/9/2015,security situation integral in economic survey of pakistan imf,business,"['ISLAMABAD', 'International', 'Monetary', 'Fund', 'IMF', 'Middle', 'East', 'Central', 'Asia', 'Masood', 'Ahmed', 'Pakistan', 'Ahmed', 'IMF', 'Pakistans', 'IMF', 'Pakistan', 'IMF', 'Pakistan']","['I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC']"
58,"LONDON: The US dollar hit multi-year highs against the euro and yen on Tuesday on the growing chance of the Federal Reserve hiking interest rates by mid-year, the prospect of which also hurt stocks and currencies from emerging markets.The skittish mood spread from Asia to Europe where stocks were down for a second day despite the European Central Bank's new bond buying campaign continuing to push down the euro and the bloc's already record-low borrowing costs.Driving the dollar up was speculation that the Federal Reserve, in contrast, will start lifting interest rates from mid-year after another round of stellar jobs data on Friday and a subsequent chorus of hawkish Fed policymaker comments.The euro's woes were compounded by worries about Greece as euro zone finance ministers met in Brussels a day after the head of the group, Jeroen Dijsselbloem, urged Athens to ""stop wasting time"" and start implementing reforms.Selling in the euro had gathered pace again in Europe as a break below a major layer of chart support at $1.0762 to $1.0735 left bears eyeing 1.07 the figure and some mulling potential parity.The dollar also broke higher on the yen in Asia to reach 122.02, territory not visited since July 2007.""It is all about the Fed now,"" said Aurelija Augulyte senior FX strategist at Nordea in Helsinki. ""The ECB (bond buying) bias has now been fully digested, but what the market is now trying to do is price in earlier Fed rate hikes.""The prospect of rising US yields threatened to draw funds away from emerging markets, causing strains from Brazil to Turkey. The Brazilian real led the rout, having fallen for the sixth straight session.The pressure spread then through Asia with the South Korean won hitting its lowest since late August 2013 and the Singapore dollar its lowest since 2010.Eastern Europe was also heavily in the red. Selling accelerated for Poland's zloty, Romania's leu and Hungary's forint and MSCI's main emerging market stock index fell 1 percent, down for its eighth day running.                        










",3/10/2015,dollar at 12 year peak vs euro emerging markets spooked,business,"['LONDON', 'US', 'Federal', 'Reserve', 'Asia', 'Europe', 'European', 'Central', 'Bank', 'Federal', 'Reserve', 'Fed', 'Greece', 'euro', 'Brussels', 'Jeroen', 'Dijsselbloem', 'Athens', 'Europe', 'Asia', 'Fed', 'Aurelija', 'Augulyte', 'FX', 'Nordea', 'Helsinki', 'ECB', 'Fed', 'US', 'Brazil', 'Turkey', 'Brazilian', 'Asia', 'South', 'Korean', 'Singapore', 'Eastern', 'Europe', 'Selling', 'Poland', 'Romania', 'Hungary', 'MSCI']","['I-ORG', 'I-MISC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-ORG']"
59,"KARACHI: Compressed Natural Gas (CNG) outlets in Sindh will remain suspended on second consecutive day Thursday.Sui Southern Gas Company (SSGC) officials said duration for closure of CNG stations across the province has been extended due to shortage of gas in the system.According to the schedule, the CNG outlets remained closed on Wednesday as well.                        









